

Sajid Ijaz

+4915772100194| sajid.ijaz92@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio

OBJECTIVE:

A self-motivated software development enthusiast with more than 5 years of experience. A results-driven and analytical individual who can think "out of the box". Interested in a challenging technical track career in an agile environment.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Languages:

PHP
 Javascript
 HTML/HTML5
 CSS/CSS

Tools and Technologies:

• Laravel • Zend • OOP • Docker • Angular • Ajax • Bootstrap • Web Scraping

Codeigniter
 REST API
 NodeJs
 Composer
 Vuejs
 JQuery
 LESS

Design/Architecture Patterns:

MVC
 Factory
 Decorator
 Observer

Version Control System:

BitBucketGitlabGithubSVN
Operating Systems
MethodologiesDatabases

Linux (Ubuntu), Windows Agile / Scrum MariaDb/ MySQL, Redis

EXPERIENCE:

Rexx Systems

Hamburg, Germany

Full Stack PHP Developer

Dec 2020 — Continued

Zameen.comSoftware Engineer
Lahore, Pakistan
Sep 2018 – Nov 2020

Propforce - Node, Angular

Propforce is a self-centered platform designed primarily for a property sale Management used by Business development officers, senior managers and departments heads to keep track of investments & revenues.

- Managed the project and database.
- Worked on new features and tasks.
- Worked on REST API.

ERPNext - Python, VueJs

- Enhanced an open source project called ERPNext.
- Override the default features using reference overriding and class inheritance.
- Increased project's overall performance using redis queues for background processing.

HRMS - Zend

- Restructured and refactored an open source project, sentrifugo.
- Optimized database structure by 50% by making summary tables and indexing the relevant tables

Leveraged Knowledge: Bitbucket, Python, VueJs, Frappe, Redis, Zend 1.12, Database Optimization, Query Optimization, ORM, Docker, Node and Angular.

Programmers Force

Lahore, Pakistan

Full Stack Developer

Mar 2018 – Aug 2018

Worked on multiple projects built in different PHP frameworks. Also worked on rest API for web application.

As a team member following duties are assign:

Worked on <u>Shuftipro</u> which is a web and mobile application which is a SAAS product offering KYC and AML verification as its basic features of operation.

- Developed in Vueis and Laravel
- Integrated 3rd party APIs

Worked on QuickBit which is a web application that is used for exchange of fiat currency to crypto currency.

- Developed in Codeigniter
- Maintained and managed the project and database
- Worked on helper functions and hooks
- Worked on new requirements and implementations

Worked on StaffTimerApp which is a web application and App that is employee monitoring software for time tracking.

- Backoffice is developed in Vuejs and Laravel
- Used Eloquent ORM for db interactions
- Used Nodejs in backoffice for live monitoring through the stafftimerapp
- Implemented Stripe payment gateway

Yonasi Lahore, Pakistan PHP Developer Jan 2017 – Feb 2018

Worked on Veraut which is a web application that is used for Energy Management and Monitoring Solution.

- Developed in Reactis and Codeigniter
- Communicated with the client directly and prepared requirement documents
- Managed the project and database

Worked on <u>EasiestEMR</u> which is a web application that is used The EMR represents a medical record within a single facility, such as a doctor's office or a clinic.

- Developed in Codeigniter, Jquery and Ajax
- Integrated 3rd party APIs

WegaWeb Lahore, Pakistan

Web Developer

Oct 2014 – May 2015
Responsible for developing custom HTML5, CSS3 and Java scripts websites, including responsiveness, fluid adaptive layouts

and email templates.

Lahore Graphic Design

Lahore, Pakistan

Web Developer

Sep 2012 – Dec2013

Being a team member, I performed analysis, coding and implementation activities of various web applications. All

being a team member, I performed analysis, coding and implementation activities of various web applications. All functional duties like planning, Implementation, Development and Maintenance.

EDUCATION:

Virtual University of Pakistan

Lahore, Pakistan

Bachelor of Computer Science (hons.) with CGPA 3.51

Sep 2012 - Sep 2016

Major Programming Courses: Data Structures, OOP, Database Management Systems, Fundamentals of Algorithms, Visual Programming, Artificial Intelligence and Data Warehousing.

CERTIFICATE AND AWARDS:

• Honored with **Employee of the Month Award** for best performance at **Yonasi**.

Certification: Web Engineering with PHP from Punjab University College of Information Technology (Sep 2012 – Nov 2012)

INTERETS:

- Keen on learning new tools and technologies
- Cricket, Badminton and Table Tennis

LANGUAGES:

- English Professional Working Proficiency
- Urdu Native
- ** REFERENCES WILL BE PROVIDED ON DEMAND**